OKay, the last curve we're going to look at is called the masse shot.
Now, that's probably what you've heard other curve shots termed as, masse shots, I like to make a difference between a natural curve shot like those that we've already explored and what is really a full masse.
Masse is just a French word, as I said earlier, this is a this game was derived by the French years and years ago.
But, the masse shot, now, is one where we're using a radical curve.
We're going to take a full half circle around the ball.
And, I've got to tell you this is not a good shot for pool.
It would be a very, very rare occasion that you would have to use it.
But the only reason that I would like to demonstrate it, or at least how it's suppose to be make, is just to show you again, the difference between the level cue rule, what we have to do to make this particular shot, and some of the extreme action you can get on a cue ball if you know how to stroke it properly.
So, with our masse shot here.
What we want to do, is we would like to be able to curve this ball, or masse this cue ball completely around that ball right there and pocket the 1 ball.
So, to do that we have to have an elevation on the cue that's pretty much vertical and know exactly where to hit the cue ball and exactly what speed to stroke it at in order to get it to do that.
Let's see what we can do with it. Whoo! Actually that's close enough. As you can see I missed the shot which might give you an indication as to just how difficult they are to make.
But once again, I do want to reiterate that this is not a shot that you really need to try to practice a whole lot, because it's not a dependable shot when you're using it in competition.
It was just really here for demonstration purposes to show you what can be done with a cue ball.
But this shot you really, you need to leave that up to the trick shot artists that you see on TV.